Guide to the Robert Moses Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1934-(1952-1970)
  - 1966: 1st volume
    - SPEECHES 1966
      - 1. Barber Shop Quartet Singing in America, Society for the Preservation and Encouragement of, St. Peter's Church, New York City, 9/20/66 (Box 6A)
      - 2. Brother Amandus Leo's Golden Jubilee, New York Hilton, 11/16/66 (Box 6A)
      - 3. Cariello, Mario, Testimonial Dinner of Queensboro Council for Social Welfare, International Hotel, Kennedy International Airport, 6/1/66 (Box 6A)
      - 4. Catholic Poetry Society Annual Dinner, Lotos Club, 10/28/66 (Box 6A)
      - 5. Co-op City Groundbreaking, Bronx, 5/14/66 (Box 6A)
      - 6. Cullman, Howard S. - State Dinner at Lotos Club, 5/10/66 (Box 6A)
      - 7. Delaware Highway Day, Eleventh Annual, Wilmington, Delaware, 9/19/66 (Box 6A)
      - 8. Edison Anchor Club 30th Annual Corporate Communion and Breakfast, Waldorf Astoria, 3/6/66 (Box 6A)
      - 9. Faith, Plans and Works, University of Massachusetts, 4/20/66 (Box 6A)
      - 10. Florida World's Fair, Authority Dinner, Miami Beach, 3/7/66 (Box 6A)
      - 11. Guggenheimer, Minnie - A Tribute - Lewisohn Stadium, New York City, 6/28/66 (Box 6A)
      - 12. Joint Center for Urban Studies of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Harvard University - Luncheon - Cambridge, Massachusetts, 11/15/66 (Box 6A)
      - 13. Morris, Newbold - Testimonial Dinner, Tavern-on-the-Green, New York City, 1/10/66 (Box 6A)
      - 14. Music Journal - Reprint of Barber Shop Quartet Society Talk of 9/20/66, 12/66 (Box 6A)
      - 15. New York Building Congress Luncheon Life Membership, St. Regis Hotel, New York City, 10/27/66 (Box 6A)
      - 16. New York Coliseum Tenth Anniversary Luncheon, Coliseum, 5/5/66 (Box 6A)
      - 17. New York World's Fair Board of Directors - Statement, 6/28/66 (Box 6A)
      - 18. New York World's Fair Board of Directors and Members, Annual Meeting, Flushing Meadow, 1/25/66 (Box 6A)
      - 19. Peters, Canon Sydney - Twentieth Anniversary at St. Peter's Church of Bay Shore, 10/21/66 (Box 6A)
      - 21. Richmond Parkway, Ceremony Marking Start of Construction on Section Two, Staten Island, 4/27/66 (Box 6A)
      - 22. Senior Citizens Center Groundbreaking, Brooklyn, 5/24/66 (Box 6A)
      - 23. Smith, Alfred E., Dedication of High School, Bronx, 12/12/66 (Box 6A)
      - 24. Space Exhibit Reopening and Inauguration of New Hall of Science, Flushing Meadow, 9/21/66 (Box 6A)
      - 25. United Housing Foundation "Slum Clearance and Cooperative Housing", Winter 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 26. University of Baltimore - "Higher Education", 11/28/66 (Box 6A)
    - 20. Prospect Park, Brooklyn, One Hundredth Anniversary, 6/2/66 (Box 6A)
  - 1966: 2nd volume
    - TBTA
      - 1. Arterial Recreation Areas for New York, 7/21/66 (Box 6A)
      - 2. Flushing Meadow Zoo and Heckscher Children's Farm - Groundbreaking Ceremony, 8/20/66 (Box 6A)
      - 3. Lincoln Center, Triborough Salutes - Fall Issue - Westsider, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 4. Memorandum in Opposition to Proposed Merger of TBTA, Transit Authority, etc., 1/21/66 (Box 6A)
      - 5. Metropolitan and Regional Area Studies - Joint Legislative Committee Testimony, 1/7/66 (Box 6A)
      - 6. New York City Building, Reopening, 7/21/66 (Box 6A)
      - 7. New York Coliseum Tenth Anniversary, 4/28/66 (Box 6A)
      - 8. Ocean Drive - Staten Island to Fire Island, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 9. Public Works and Beauty, 4/4/66 (Box 6A)
      - 10. Rails Against Rubber - Memorandum, 4/1/66 (Box 6A)
      - 11. Saga of Flushing Meadow, 4/11/66 (Box 6A)
      - 12. Three Decades of Service, 7/11/66 (Box 6A)
      - 13. Transportation Consolidation Functions - Joint Public Hearings - Statements in Opposition to Proposed Bills, 3/10-11/66 (Box 6A)
      - 14. Triborough Act - Statement to Committee on State Legislation of the City Council, 5/23/66 (Box 6A)
      - 15. Triborough Bridge 1936-1966, 7/11/66 (Box 6A)
      - 16. Verrazano-Narrows Bridge Second Birthday Statement for Staten Island Advance, 11/9/66 (Box 6A)
  - 1966: 3rd volume
    - 1966 NEWSDAY COLUMNS
      - 1. New Republics, January 8, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 2. Parks and the New Rich, January 15, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 3. Conflict of Interest, January 22, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 4. 20 Questions on Southeast Asia, January 29, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 5. Facing College, February 5, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 6. Public Statuary, February 12, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 7. Trujillo - Hemisphere Symbol, February 19,1966 (Box 6A)
      - 8. A Rose is a Rose, February 26,1966 (Box 6A)
      - 9. Ad Hoc, March 5, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 10. Slum Clearance, March 12, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 11. Gadgets in Government, March 19, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 12. Commitment in the Far East, March 26, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 13. Stretching the Seasons, April 2, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 14. Parks and Cemeteries, April 9, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 15. The Trend: A Dramatic Monologue, April 16, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 16. Conservation - Pretension and Practice, April 23, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 17. Space Exploration and Atomic Energy, April 30, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 18. In Fond Memory - Henry Louis Mencken, May 7, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 19. How to Succeed, May 14, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 20. Jones Beach After 40 Years, May 21, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 21. More About Will Cuppy, May 28, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 22. A Week in Ireland: The Kerry Ring and Killarney, June 4, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 23. A '38 Delegate Looks Back - And Ahead, June 11, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 24. Hitler's Keitel, June 18, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 25. Speed and Safety, June 25, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 26. Hudson Hysteria, July 2, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 27. Comes the Millennium, July 9, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 28. Ferment in the Church, July 16, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 29. The Battles Long Ago, July 23, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 30. Liberty and License, July 30, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 31. Water, Water Everywhere, August 6, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 32. Where are we Headed? Three Passing Reflections, August 13, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 33. Weed, Tides and Waste on the South Shore of Long Island, August 20, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 34. Mitchel Field and Higher Education, August 27, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 35. Home Work in the Slums: A Plan for North Amityville, September 3, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 36. Hurricanes and Beach Buggies, September 10, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 37. Breezy Point: Fiasco or Treasure?, September 17, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 38. Peak Loads, September 24, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 39. The American Core, October 1, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 40. The Grand Assizes, October 8, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 41. The American Language, October 15, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 42. Musical Note: Marine Theaters, October 22, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 43. Farms Along Southern State Parkway, October 29, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 44. Atomic Long Island, November 5, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 45. Foxes in Ireland, November 12, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 46. Voter Interest: The Long Ballot, An After Election Tally, November 19, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 47. Kennedy Campaigning, November 26, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 48. Private Golf Course on Long Island, December 3, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 49. Briefing in Washington, December 10, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 50. Golf Clubs Again, December 17, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 51. One Nation, One Vote, December 24, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 52. The Sound Crossing, December 31, 1966 (Box 6A)
    - 1966 MISCELLANEOUS
      - 1 & 2. Florida - Number One at the Fair, 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 3. Flushing Meadow, Show at, 4/9/66 (Box 6A)
      - 4. Hall of Science, June 1966 (Box 6A)
      - 5. Jersey Journal - "Evening With Moses", 12/5/66 (Box 6A)
  - 1967 1st volume
    - SPEECHES 1967
      - 1. Boy Scouts Suffolk County Council Distinguished Citizen Award, Huntington, L. I., 12/12 (Box 6B)
      - 2. Brooklyn Heights Association Award, Brooklyn, N.Y., 5/15/67 (Box 6B)
      - 3. Coliseum Opening of New Dining Facilities, 9/26 (Box 6B)
      - 4. Committee on Economic Development of the 1967 Constitutional Convention Public Hearing, Albany, 6/13 (Box 6B)
      - 5. Committee on Intergovernmental Relations 1967 Constitutional Convention - Statement, 6/13 (Box 6B)
      - 6. Committee on Economic Development of the Constitutional Convention on the State's Role in Development of Power, Albany, 7/19 (Box 6B)
      - 7. Construction Man of the Year Award, Boy Scouts Lunch-O-Ree, Americana Hotel, 2/2 (Box 6B)
      - 8. Department of Transportation Meeting - Statement Washington, D. C., 6/29 (Box 6B)
      - 9. Dutch Treat Club Luncheon, Regency Hotel, New York, 1/17 (Box 6B)
      - 10. Esquire Round Table Luncheon, New York City, 11/15 (Box 6B)
      - 11. Fordham 126th Anniversary Dinner, Waldorf Astoria, 1/24 (Box 6B)
      - 12. Hall of Science Groundbreaking Ceremony, Flushing Meadows, 6/3 (Box 6B)
      - 13. Iona College Award Dinner Dance, Hotel Americana, 11/1 (Box 6B)
      - 14. Mary Manning Walsh Home Volunteers Association, New York City, 9/28 (Box 6B)
      - 15. Morris, Newbold - Unveiling of Plaque at City Center, New York City, 1/23 (Box 6B)
      - 16. National Commission on Urban Problems, New York City, 9/8 (Box 6B)
      - 17. Newsday's National Newspaperboy Day Celebration, Bay Shore, L. I., 10/28 (Box 6B)
      - 18. New York State County Highway Superintendents Association, Lido Beach, N. Y., 9/7 (Box 6B)
      - 19. New York World's Fair 1964-1965 Statement to the Board of Directors and Members, Annual Meeting, 1/25 (Box 6B)
      - 20. Players Club Columnists' Pipe Night, New York City, 5/14 (Box 6B)
      - 21. President's Club, Dayton, Ohio, 11/1 (Box 6B)
      - 22. Queensboro Council for Social Welfare Annual Dinner, International Hotel, Kennedy Airport, 5/18 (Box 6B)
      - 23. Regis High School Alumni Association Communion Breakfast, Waldorf Astoria, 2/5 (Box 6B)
      - 24. Ridder, Victor, Dedication of Memorial Room, Isabella House, New York City, 11/8 (Box 6B)
      - 25. Sarnoff, General David - 291st State Dinner, Lotos Club, 4/5 (Box 6B)
      - 26. Savings Banks Public Relations Forum of New York State, St. Moritz Hotel, New York City, 1/19 (Box 6B)
      - 27. Senior Citizens Center, Fort Hamilton Playground - Dedication - Brooklyn, 1/21 (Box 6B)
      - 28. Suffolk County Village Officials Association, Dinner, Port Jefferson, 5/25 (Box 6B)
      - 29. Unisphere Friendship Scout-O-Ree Opening Ceremony, Flushing Meadows, 6/10 (Box 6B)
      - 30. Vatican Pavilion Exedra Dedication, Flushing Meadows, 6/3 (Box 6B)
      - 31. Vest Pocket Park, 29th St. and Second Ave., New York City - Dedication, 7/21 (Box 6B)
      - 32. Washington, George - Statue Unveiling at Masonic Brotherhood Site, Flushing Meadows, 6/3 (Box 6B)
  - 1967: 2nd volume
    - NEWSDAY COLUMNS - 1967
      - 1. "Suburban Long Island Zoning", January 7, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 2. "Sweepstakes and Education", Part I, January 14, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 3. "Sweepstakes and Education", Part II, January 21, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 4. "Cays Under the Sun, January 28, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 5. "Program and Performance", February 4, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 6, "Opening the Adirondack and Catskill Parks: A Job for the Constitutional Convention - Part I, February 11, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 7. "Opening the Adirondack and Catskill Parks: A Job for the Constitutional Convention - Part II, February 18, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 8. "Montauk Revisited", February 25, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 9. "Water Transportation Subsidies", March 4, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 10. "Suffolk Sewers", March 11, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 11. "The Central Park Reservoir", March 18, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 12. "Katzenback and Crime", March 25, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 13. "The Convention Opens, April 1, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 14. "Suffolk Separation", April 8, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 15. "Metropolitan Transportation", April 15, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 16. "The Science Center at Flushing Meadow", April 22, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 17. "Epcot: Walt Disney's Legacy", April 29, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 18. "Spies" - Part I, May 6, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 19. "Spies" - Part II, May 13, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 20. "Academic Ferment - Who Picks the Chancellors?", May 20, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 21. "Brig. Gen. Sarnoff - American", May 27, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 22. "New Man in Town", June 3, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 23. "The Presidency", June 10, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 24. "Father's Day", June 17, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 25. "The Genius of The Atomic Submarine", June 24, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 26. "A Federal Constitutional Amendment on Apportionment", July 1, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 27. "Science and Guff", July 8, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 28. "Park Litter", July 15, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 29. "Fill Versus Fire", July 22, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 30. "The Coming Labor Courts", July 29, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 31. "Reflections on the Passing of a Long Island Doctor", August 5, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 32. "Reflections on The Puerto Rican Election", August 12, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 33. "Roll, Jordan, Roll", August 19, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 34. "Slums Must Go" - Part I, August 26, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 35. "Slums Must Go" - Part II, September 2, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 36. "Osaka Coming Up", September 9, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 37. "Public Authorities and the Albany Convention", September 16, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 38. "Another Season Ends at Jones Beach Theater", September 23, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 39. "An Ex-Judge Tells How to Improve the Bench", September 30, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 40. "Correspondence With the Big Weatherman", October 7, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 41. "New York's 1967 Convention Lacked Class", October 14, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 42. "The City Club and 75 Years of NY History", October 21, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 43. "Why NY Needs the Transportation Bond Issue", October 28, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 44. "The Brookhaven Lab: A Window on The Future", November 4, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 46. "Fast Action is Needed to Ease Crowded Skies", November 18, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 47. "The '68 Mexican Olympics: Fast vs. Rumor", November 25, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 48. "Wanted: Private Places for Public Parks", November 25, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 49. "Daily Press Must Fight Creeping Vulgarity", December 2, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 50. "The Passing of New York's Great Cardinal", December 9, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 51. "Winter Cruises Offer a Variety of Pleasures", December 16, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 52. "Western LI Sound Bridge Should be Built Now", December 23, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 53. "On the Brink of 1968, A Year of Big Decisions", December 30, 1967 (Box 6B)
    - ARTICLES AND MISCELLANEOUS
      - 1. Daily News - "Constitution Battle Page", 11/3/67 (Box 6B)
      - 2. Daily News - "Inquiring Photographer", June 7, 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 3. Aymar Embury II - Unveiling of Plaque, 10/17/67 (Box 6B)
      - 4. Empire State Architect, Staten Island Issue "Parks and Highways for Staten Island", Jan/February 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 5. Good Samaritan Ball - Good Samaritan Hospital West Islip, L.I., 8/26/67 (Box 6B)
      - 6. Ingenor 2 - "Knowledge and the Deed", Spring 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 7. New York Times Reprint - "Barbershop Fans Welcome Moses" - Manhattan Skyline, 3/1/67 (Box 6B)
      - 8. "Rochdale Village - A New Concept in Community Living", November 1967 (Box 6B)
      - 9. Saturday Review - "Confessions of a Reformed Reformer", 1/7/67 (Box 6B)
  - 1967: 3rd volume
    - TRIBOROUGH BROCHURES
      - 1. 1967 Annual Report, 2/19/68 (Box 6B)
      - 2. "A Study of Metropolitan New York Transportation" by Madigan-Hyland, 3/20/67 (Box 6B)
      - 3. "Flushing Meadows-Corona Park" - Public Ceremonies, 6/3/67 (Box 6B)
      - 4. "Opening of Brooklyn-Queens Expressway Playgrounds", 6/28/67 (Box 6B)
      - 5. "Financial and Construction Program 1967-1971", 7/10/67 (Box 6B)
      - 6. "Lower Level Roadway Addition to Verrazano-Narrows Bridge", 11/2/67 (Box 6B)
      - 7. "Sunken Meadow - Randall's Island", 12/18/67 (Box 6B)
      - Public Works: A Dangerous Trade, 1970 (Box 6B)
      - Loose materials, 1934-1969, undated (Box 7)
- Addition 11/9/81, 1968-1970
  - Notebooks containing Newsday columns, articles, speeches, Triborough Brochures, 1968-1970 (Box 8)